RESUME

BASANT KUMAR GUPTA

E-mail: <u>basantgupta370@gmail.com</u>
Mobile: 7999541779 7974710416

Local address – Vinayak Multi Homes Near Coach Factory Bhopal (M.P)

OBJECTIVE:-

Scaling new heights of success with hard work & dedication and leaving a mark of excellence on every step; aiming for assignments which involve analytical capabilities and professional growth in Operation & Maintenance with a reputed organization.

Electrical Engineer With 8+ Years' experience in varied project including 765kv ,400kv,220kv,& 132kv substation and transmission line Operation & Maintenance Ready to collaborate on complex ongoing project or create new initiatives from scratch

Key Responsibilities

- 1) Operation and Maintenance of Substation and Transmission line of 765kv 400kv 220kv & 132kv
- 2) INDIAN RAILWAY SUBSTATION PROJECT Erection of traction Substation 132/25KV Substation
- 3) Good knowledge of Substation & Prepared of Fault Analysis report
- 4) Prepare Daily Progress Report of all the Sites and Send it to Head Office
- 5) Project Execution and Monitoring
- 6) Fire Alarm System of Substation
- 7) All Maintenance of Substation and Transmission line of 765kv 400kv 220kv & 132kv
- 8) Overall Site Management and coordination for successful and timely completion of project
- 9) Business Development activates
- 10) Client Relationship
- 11) Clearing the Bill of the Project from the Government office or Client office
- 12) Handling Project Contractors
- 13) Arrangement of Main Power
- 14) Material Purchase
- 15) Tender Costing and Documents Uploading work
- 16) Project Management & Planning
- 17) Project Execution and Monitoring

Work Experience

Name of Company: JBS ENTERPRISES

Designation: Project Manager

Working Period: DEC 2021 TO TILL DATE

Bay Erection of 220/132KV Substation

- 1) Project Management of Substation Erection Work of Substation
- 2) Billing Work Manpower arrangement and client Relationship
- 3) Project Cost Analysis and other work
- 4) Tendering Work

Work Experience

Name of Company: SANFIELD INDIA LTD Designation: Project Manager

Working Period: April 2021 TO Nov 2021 INDIAN RAILWAY PROJECT - Erection of 132/25KV Substation

handling and planning Manager Communication has to be done with all government officer Overall Project Management, Co - ordination between H.O & Site, Execution of work strictly following QMS & Safety, Work Scheduling & Progress Monitoring, Prep. of critical task , sourcing & risk mitigation , Preliminary review of Drawings & Documents , Timely delivery and achievement of milestones , Client Handling & Claim Settlement , Equipment Erection & Testing Commissioning Assistance , Preparation of JMC,MB & Raising Bills , Setting up Technical Specification , Certification of Subcontractor Bill, Work , Strategic Sourcing & Procurement , Establishment of Claims as per Contract , Sharing knowledge & Group Work , Data & Value feeding to Tender Committee , Execution from Site Level and Vendor Control & Co - ordination .

Work Experience

Name of Company: JBS ENTERPRISES PVT

Designation: DY. Manage

Working Period: April 2021 TO Nov 2021 INDIAN RAILWAY PROJECT -Erection of 132/25KV Substation

JOB PROFILE: -

25 no Substation handled 220 kv and 10no Substation handled of 132kv and 15 no CSPTCL PROJECT Looking whole O&M activities for substations transmission lines 300 Manpower Handling

- 1) purchase & Business development activities in all along with transmission line attending transmission line shutdown main power arranging main power handling and planning Manager Communication has to be done with all government officer and Business Developer
- 2) Clearing the Bill of the Project from the Government office
- 3) Tender Costing Tender documents and tender uploading work
- 4) 75% Traveling work

Name of Company: ELITE POWERTECH PVT LTD

Designation: Ast. Manager

Working Period: March 2017 to NOV 2019

765kv Power Grid CHAMPA

JOB PROFILE: -

- 1') Preparation of shift Schedules and Preparation of daily progress reports
 . Preparation of Fault Analysis report. Knowledge of PTW
- 2) SF6 Gas Circuit Breaker, Bus-bar maintenance.
- 3) Preparation of Annual and monthly maintenance schedule.
- 4) To communicate between NRLDC & WLDC for shut down purpose and to obtain charging & tripping code.
- 5) Arranging Preventive Maintenance Schedule for AC & DC UPS, Transformer, Reactor, CT, PT and SF6 Gas Circuit Breaker.
- 6) Preparation of Fault Analysis report. Knowledge of PTW system.
- 7) Centralize operating & monitoring of Electrical Distribution system, SCADA system.
- 8) Proficiency in managing the Erection, Commissioning & maintenance of EHV Sub-Station Switch Yard Equipment's

Name of Company: JBS ENTERPRISES PVT LTD

Designation: SR.ENGINEER

Working Period: JAN 2013 TO March 2017 400/220/133 kv Substation DEEDWANA (R.J)

JOB PROFILE:-

- Operation & Maintenance and full Site Supervision of 400kV switch yard equipment, SF6 Gas Circuit Breaker, Bus-bar maintenance.
- Preparation of Annual and monthly maintenance schedule.
- To communicate between NRLDC & SLDC for shut down purpose and to obtain charging & tripping code.
- Arranging Preventive Maintenance Schedule for AC & DC UPS, Transformer,
 Reactor, CT, PT and SF6 Gas Circuit Breaker.
- Prepared of Fault Analysis report. Knowledge of PTW system.
- Centralize operating & monitoring of Electrical Distribution system, SCADA system.
- To perform various testing like CRM, TAN δ, IR, Transformer Oil BDV, Polarity,
 LA leakage current, Ratio & Stability.
- To maintain record, log books for the jobs carried out & To record power system parameters on regular basis & maintain records also, To work on Manual synchronizing panel, disturbance recorder etc. and control all parameters.
- Hands on Experience of SF6 Gas Circuit Breaker Maintenance.
- Good knowledge of station & equipment grounding as principal requirement for sub-station.
- Preparing site planning according to fixed targets.
- Executing site activities, as well as coordinating with client & back office.
- Cross checking the approved drawings before execution and according to site conditions making modifications as per standard manner and preparing documentation for which was deviated from approved drawings.
- Solutions and engineering backup for any deviations.

Technical vender selection and management.

Quality management and cost control.

- Resources tackle and train new engineers.
- Developing safety in site.
- Planning for shutdown activities like relocation of 400kV Line equipment's,

KEY SKILLS: -

➤ Capacitance and TAN-delta measurement test of Transformer Bushing (315MVA & 100 MVA) and CVT (245 KV & 145 KV), Operating timing measurement test of Circuit Breaker (420KV, 245KV & 145KV), Contact resistance measurement (CRM) test of Circuit Breaker & Isolators

- (420KV, 245KV & 145KV) and Earth Switch, **Primary injection or Ratio** Test of CT, **IR Value** test, **BDV** test. &**TFR** test.
- ➢ Operation & trouble shooting maintenance of Panels, Battery bank (48 V & 220 V) &Diesel Generator Set (250 KVA)
- Preventive & Breakdown Maintenance of Transformers.
- > Testing of CT, SF₆ Circuit Breaker, CVT, Isolators, HV & LV cables and electrical control panels.
- Analyze of faulty circuit after tripping and prepare **Disturbing Records (DR)** report and **event logger** and tripping details.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

Technical Qualification: -

COURSE NAME	UNIVERSITY	YEAR OF PASSING	% OF MARKS
Bachelor of		•	60 - 60/
Engineering	Rajiv Gandhi Technical University,	2011	60.56%
(B.E.) In	Bhopal		
Electrical Engineering	(RGTU)		
Diploma of	Rajiv Gandhi Technical University,	2007	64.46%
Engineering	Bhopal		
Electrical Engineering	(RGTU)		

SKILLS: -

Software skills: -

- Basic knowledge on SCADA, AUTOCAD
- MS Office.

LEISURE INTERESTS: -

> Travelling, Playing chess & cooking

PERSONAL DETAILS: -

Permanent Address: S.B.I Colony Near Amba Hospital Chinaware (M.P.)

Date of Birth : 13July 1985

Sex: MaleMarital Status: marriedNationality: Indian

Linguistics Abilities : English (Speak, Read, Write), & Hindi (Speak, Read, Write)

I do hereby declare that all the above statements are true to the best of my knowledge andbelief.

Name -: Basant Gupta

Date

•